Encounters are mysterious! But the world is even more so!
لقاءات البشر مغلّفة بالغموض، والعالم تلفّه طبقات أكثر حتّى
I'm so glad I'm with you!
!أنا مسرورٌ حقّاً لكوني معك
Today's stage is a school at night!
!مسرح اليوم هو المدرسة ليلاً
Scary rumors flow through the darkness!
!تحوم شائعات مخيفة في مجرى الليل
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
This school is cursed?
هذه المدرسة ملعونة؟
Yeah! It's really for reals!
!أجل، إنّها الحقيقة
The whole school's talking about it!
!المدرسة بأسرها تتكلّم عنها
I bet it's just another of those "Seven Mysteries" every school has.
"لا بد أنّها إحدى "الألغاز السبعة التي توجد في كلّ مدرسة
Like pianos that play on their own, or stairs that increase in number.
،مثل البيانو الذي يُعزف من تلقاء نفسه والأدراج التي يرتفع عددها
This isn't that kind of childish rubbish!
!ليست كلاماً طفوليّاً كهذا
It happened early one morning last week,
حدث الأمر في الصباح الباكر الأسبوع الفائت
when a student went into the art room.
عندما دخلت تلميذةٌ غرفة الفنون
She was fond of a large painting in the art room,
كانت تحبّ اللوحات الكبيرة في غرفة الفنون
and she went to look at it every morning.
وتذهب كلّ صباح للتحديق فيها
But then she saw it...
...لكنّها رأت
All eight plaster figures in the art room were glaring at her!
كلّ التماثيل الجصّية الثمانية !في غرفة الفنون تحدّق فيها
What do you think? Mysterious, isn't it?!
ما رأيك؟ أليس غامضاً؟
It was just coincidence.
إنّها مجرد مصادفة، مصادفة
And it isn't just her!
!ليس هي فقط
Doesn't there seem to be fewer students at this school lately?!
ألا ترى أنّ عدد التلامذة انخفض في هذه المدرسة مؤخراً؟
I heard there was a cold going around.
سمعتُ أنّ الزكام منتشر
Who knows, maybe they've all been cursed by the plaster figures!
!ربما أصابتهم جميعاً لعنة التماثيل الجصّية
The story I heard is much crazier than those plaster figures!
الشائعة التي سمعتُها أقوى !من تلك التماثيل الجصّية
You know that gross doll in the nurse's office?
أتعرف تلك الدمية المقرفة في مكتب الممرضة؟
Oh, the anatomy model?
تقصد نموذج التشريح؟
It was running super-fast through the hallway four nights ago!
...كان يركض
That's dumb.
يا للسخافة
Hey! Ayumi! Tell him your story, too!
!أيومي! أخبريه بقصّتك أيضاً
Huh? You saw something too, Ayumi-chan?
ماذا؟ رأيتِ شيئاً أيضاً يا أيومي-تشان؟
Y-Yeah.
أجل
Anyways, we gotta do a Junior Detective League investigation
بأيّ حال، علينا نحن فرقة فتيان التحرّي البدء
before things get really bad!
!بالتحقيق وإلّا قد تقع كارثة
K-Kobayashi-sensei!
!كوباياشي سينسي
If you can't behave in my class,
،إذا لم تستطع التهذّب أثناء درسي
Kobayashi Sumiko (26) Class 1-B Homeroom Teacher
(كوباياشي سوميكو (26 معلّمة الفصل 1-ب المشرفة
then leave this instant!
!فارحل فوراً
Fukumoto-kun! Read the next one!
!حسناً، اقرأ أنت تالياً يا فوكوموتو-كن
Come on! Quit dilly-dallying!
!هيّا! لا تتباطأ
Yes, ma'am!
!حاضر
What's your problem, hag?
ما مشكلتك أيّتها العجوز الشيطانة؟
Totani-sensei was so much better. She was actually nice.
كانت توتاني سينسي أفضل، ألطف بكثير
There's nothing we can do. She got married and quit her job.
ليس باليد حيلة، فقد تزوّجت وتركت عملها
This is so lame.
هذا بائس
Ayumi-chan?
أيومي-تشان؟
Eh? You saw a strange person?
ماذا؟ رأيتِ شخصاً غريباً؟
Yeah. In this classroom, three nights ago.
أجل، في غرفة الفصل هذه قبل ثلاثة أيام
Why were you at school at night?
لمَ أتيتِ للمدرسة ليلاً؟
I couldn't help it. I was worried about the fishies.
كنت... قلقةً على السمك
Fish? You mean them?
السمك؟ تقصدين هذه؟
Yeah. I forgot to feed them that day, so I came to check on them.
أجل، نسيتُ إطعامها ذاك اليوم فرجعت لتفقّد حالها
And then I saw someone in this classroom, in the pitch dark!
!ورأيتُ شخصاً في غرفة الفصل هذه المظلمة
They were wandering around creepy-like, with a big, white mask on!
!كان مريباً ويتجوّل بقناع أبيض كبير
Did you see their face?!
هل رأيتِ وجهه؟
No... I couldn't tell by their voice, either.
كلا، كان صوته مكتوماً أيضاً فلم أتعرّف عليه
They seemed to be mad, though.
لكنّه بدا غاضباً
Why didn't you tell this to a teacher?!
لمَ لم تخبري معلّماً بذلك؟
I did! I told the assistant principal, he lives in my neighborhood!
فعلت! أخبرت نائب المدير الذي !يعيش في حيّنا
He promised to look into it.
وعد بتفقّد الأمر
So, what did he find out?
وما الذي وجده؟
That's just it... He hasn't come to school yesterday or today!
في الواقع... لم يأت للمدرسة !اليوم ولا بالأمس
Kobayashi-sensei and the other teachers said they haven't seen him,
سألت كوباياشي سينسي وبقيّة المعلّمين وقالوا أنّهم لم يروه
and nobody answered the doorbell when I went to his house!
ولم يجب أحدٌ على الجرس !عندما ذهبتُ لمنزله
Are you sure he isn't in bed with a cold?
ألا يمكن أنّه طريح الفراش بالزكام لا أكثر؟
He would've contacted the school if that were the case.
كان ليتّصل بالمدرسة في تلك الحالة
As I recall, he lives alone after his wife passed away...
وفقما أذكر، فهو يعيش بمفرده ...بعدما تُوفيّت زوجته
It... It must be my fault!
!لا بد... لا بد أنّها غلطتي
It's because of what I asked him that that strange person killed him!
!بسبب ما طلبتُه منه، قتله ذاك الشخص الغريب
Hey, you! What's all the ruckus?! Get cleaning!
!أنتم! لمَ هذه الجلبة؟ فلتبدؤوا التنظيف
And you'll all take Open House notices to your sick friends afterward!
وعليكم توصيل إشعارات الفصل المفتوح !لمنزل صديقكم المتغيّب اليوم
Is that clear?!
أفهمتم؟
Yes, ma'am...
...حسناً
Ohata Masayuki (31) Class 1-A Homeroom Teacher
(أوهاتا ماسايوكي (31 معلّم الفصل 1-أ المشرف
Dealing with 1st graders right off the bat
قد يكون التعامل مع طلّاب الصفّ الأوّل
after being transferred here must be tough, but you should be more easygoing.
فور انتقالك هنا صعباً، لكن عليكِ الاسترخاء أكثر
No, that isn't the case.
لا، ليس الأمر هكذا
Say, Ohata-sensei. Can I ask you something?
،أخبرني يا أوهاتا سينسي هل لي أن أسألك شيئاً؟
Sure, what is it?
أجل، ما الأمر؟
Do you know what's happened to the assistant principal?
أتعرف ما الذي حلّ بنائب المدير؟
U-Uhh... I-I don't know!
!ذ-ذلك... لا-لا أدري
He's been absent for two days without notice,
،يبدو إنّه غائبٌ ليومين بلا إشعار
but I'm sure he'll show up sooner or later!
!لكنّي أظنّه سيظهر عاجلاً أم آجلاً
He's hiding something.
إنّه يخفي شيئاً
Darn it! They're all a bunch of creepy big-shots!
!تبّاً! كلّهم جماعة معلّمين بغيضين
Now, now! Do not kick the school building so!
!أنت، لا تركل مبنى المدرسة هكذا
Principal!
!حضرة المدير
Uematsu Ryujiro (59) Teitan Elem. School Principal
(أويماتسو ريوجيرو (59 مديرة مدرسة تيتان الابتدائيّة
This school building will already be thirty this year.
سيبلغ مبنى هذه المدرسة عامه الثلاثين هذا الحول
I've shared many hard times with it. It may as well be my double.
،تشاركتُ معه العديد من الأوقات العصيبة لذا هو بمثابة ذاتي الأخرى
Please be kinder to it.
هلّا عاملتموه بلطفٍ أكبر
Umm, have you seen the assistant principal?
المعذرة، هل تعرف أمر النائب حضرة المدير؟
Secrets will always get out. He was truly unlucky.
محتّمٌ على الأسرار أن تتسرّب، كان سيّئ الحظّ بحقّ
It was fate.
إنّه القدر
Alright! Got it, you guys?!
حسناً، تفهمان ما سنفعله، صحيح؟
Yeah!
!أجل
We, the Detective League, will now break into the school...
...سنتسلّل نحن فرقة فتيان التحرّي لمبنى المدرسة
...to solve the many mysteries that have happened here!
!لحلّ الألغاز العديدة التي وقعت هنا
I believe this is the one I left unlocked...
أظنّ هذه كانت التي تركتها غير مقفلة
Hey! That's not fair!
!هذا ليس منصفاً
Let us in, Conan-kun!
!افتح لنا يا كونان-كن
It's dangerous, so go on home.
هذا خطر، فلترجعوا للبيت
Heave... ho!
...استعداد
Okay, okay! I'll let you in!
!حسناً، حسناً! سأفتح لكم
Schools at night sure are creepy...
المدرسة ليلاً مخيفة حقّاً
Yeah! My heart's pounding!
!أجل! قلبي ينبض بشدّة
Let's keep this a secret. If the teachers found out...
...لنتكتّم على الأمر، لو اكتشف المعلّمون هذا
No, it's already obvious.
كلا، أنتم مكشوفون سلفاً
Especially if you're wearing muddy shoes.
خصوصاً بما أنّكم ترتدون أحذية موحلة
Geez. What a nuisance they can be...
يا إلهي، يا للجماعة المُتعِبة
Okay! Let's go!
!حسناً، هيّا بنا
Let's start with the art room!
!لنبدأ بغرفة الفنون
Yeah!
!أجل
Lights, lights!
!الأنوار، الأنوار
Don't!
!كلا
We'll be spotted if we turn the lights on!
!سنُكشف إذا فتحت الأنوار
At least bring a flashlight for stuff like this.
عليكم جلب مصباح يدويّ على الأقل
I brought one, too!
أحضرتُ واحداً بالفعل
There they are! The plaster figures!
!تلك هي! هذه التماثيل الجصّية
There's a mark where the desk and figure meet...
يوجد أثران بموضع التقاء التمثال والطاولة
It looks like Mitsuhiko's story wasn't just a rumor.
يبدو أنّ قصّة ميتسوهيكو لم تكن مجرّد شائعة
What's that? There's something stuck to the figure's forehead...
ما هذا؟ يوجد شيءٌ ملتصق على جبهة التمثال
A piece of tape?
شريط لاصق؟
I don't think there's anything here.
لا يبدو أنّه يوجد شيءٌ هنا
Then should we check out the nurse's office next?
هل نتّجه لمكتب الممرضة تالياً إذاً؟
Yeah.
أجل
Let's see... Anatomy model, anatomy model...
حسناً، نموذج تشريح، نموذج تشريح
How odd. I don't see it anywhere.
هذا غريب، إنّه ليس موجوداً
Don't tell me it's running through the hallway, like the rumors say!
أيمكن أنّه يركض في الرواق كما جاء في الشائعات؟
Ayumi-chan!
!أيومي-تشان
Ayumi!
!أيومي
Ouch...
...مؤلم
Are you okay, Ayumi-chan?!
أأنتِ بخير يا أيومي-تشان؟
Yeah...
أجل
But I dropped my handkerchief somewhere...
لكن يبدو أنّي أسقطت ...منديلي في مكانٍ ما
What's that?
ما ذلك؟
A doll! I think it came from this box!
!دمية! أظنّها كانت في هذا الصندوق
Hey, yeah! Awesome!
!بالفعل! مذهل
Another class must've used them for a puppet play!
لا بدّ أنّ فصلاً في السابق !استعملها في مسرحية دمى
But it's strange... Why is this out here?
لكن هذا غريب، لمَ يوجد الصندوق في الخارج؟
Look! This Xuanzang doll has the same name as me!
!انظروا! لدمية سانزوهوشي هذه مثل اسمي الأخير
And this Sha Wujing has my name!
!واسمي على ساكوجو
Bah. I'm stuck with Zhu Bajie?
!الرأس مقطوع
It's not just the head!
!ليس الرأس وحده
The whole doll is really beat up!
!الدمية بأسرها في حالة يُرثى لها
H-Hey! Don't tell me someone's out to get me?!
!أ-أيمكن أنّ أحدهم يستهدفني؟
It just happens to have your name!
!صادف أنّها تحمل اسمك الأخير لا أكثر
Yes! It was probably the name of the student using it in the play!
أجل! كان اسم أحد التلامذة !المشاركين في المسرحية غالباً
No, not necessarily.
كلا، ليس بالضرورة
Look... Edogawa isn't that common of a name.
انظروا، اسم إيدوغاوا ليس شائعاً
You're not suggesting this is connected to the drop in students lately?
أيمكن أنّ هذا متّصل بانخفاض عدد التلامذة مؤخراً؟
D-Does that mean I'm the next to go?!
!أيعني ذلك أنّي الضحيّة التالية؟
It's not like that! We're just being misled by the rumors!
!ليس كذلك! ضلّلتنا الشائعات لا أكثر
After all, the plaster figures were in the art room...
كما أنّ التماثيل الجصّية كانت !في غرفة الفنون
...and the anatomy model is in the nurse's office!
!ونموذج التشريح في مكتب الممرضة
Mitsuhiko!
!ميتسوهيكو
What?!
!ماذا؟
What?! I don't see it anywhere!
!أين هو؟ لا أراه في أيّ مكان
But I really saw it!
!لكنّي رأيتُه للتوّ
Hey! Conan! Wait up!
!أنت! كونان! انتظر
See, it's right there!
!إنّه هنا كما ترى
You probably just saw something else!
لا بدّ أنّ الخوف جعلك !ترى شيئاً آخر
No. Look at the base of this anatomy model.
كلا، انظروا لقاعدة نموذج التشريح هذا
Class 1-B, Yoshida Ayumi
الفصل 1-ب، يوشيدا أيومي
The handkerchief Ayumi-chan dropped earlier is stuck under it.
المنديل الذي أسقطته أيومي-تشان قبل قليل عالق أسفله
In other words, this model moved after we left the nurse's office.
أي أنّ هذا النموذج قد حُرّك بعدما غادرنا مكتب الممرضة
Then... it moved on its own?
تحرّك من تلقاء نفسه إذاً؟
Don't be stupid. Someone obviously moved it.
لا تكوني حمقاء، حرّكه أحدهم بلا شكّ
But why would someone do that?!
لكن لمَ قد يفعل ذلك؟
Don't tell me they're trying to scare us!
أيمكن أنّه يحاول إخافتنا؟
If that were the case, they wouldn't have put it back where it was!
،لو كان يحاول إخافتنا فحسب لما أعاده لمكانه الأصليّ
What a relief that it wasn't a ghost!
لكن حمداً لله، لم تكن فعلة شبح، صحيح؟
What's creepier than a ghost
ما يثير الاشمئزاز أكثر من شبح
is the person sneaking around school, doing odd things at this hour!
هو شخص يتسلّل في هذا الوقت في المدرسة !ويقوم بأشياء غريبة
Who's there?!
!من هناك؟
What is it, Conan?!
ما الأمر يا كونان؟
Someone was looking this way from the opposite window!
!رأيت ظلّ أحدهم ينظر لنا من النافذة المقابلة
What? There's no one there...
ماذا؟ لا أحد هنا
There couldn't have been anyone!
يستحيل أنّه كان موجوداً
I saw the anatomy model from the window facing the nurse's office!
فقد رأيتُ نموذج التشريح من النافذة !المقابلة لمكتب الممرضة
If the intruder heard my scream, quickly put the anatomy model back,
إذا سمع الفاعل صرختي، وأعاد النموذج لمكانه سريعاً
and then watched through this window,
ثمّ راقب من هذه النافذة
we would've bumped into them on our way to the nurse's office!
!فكنّا لنلتقيه في طريقنا لمكتب الممرضة
You must've been seeing things.
لا بدّ أنّها كانت مخيلتك يا كونان-كن
No. Someone was definitely here.
كلا، كان أحدهم هنا بلا شكّ
See! The window!
!انظري، هذه النافذة
The window?
النافذة؟
See the white smudge?
أترين البقعة البيضاء؟
It's proof that someone was pressed against the window, looking out!
!إنّها دليلٌ على التصاق أحدهم بالنافذة، واستراقه النظر
Anyway, we're in danger all by ourselves!
بأيّ حال، نحن في خطر بأنفسنا
Let's get the security guard here!
لنطلب قدوم الحارس هنا
Let's see, where is there a phone?
...حسناً، كان الهاتف في
Hurry, Conan-kun!
!أسرع يا كونان-كن
Why is the faculty office unlocked?!
لمَ باب مكتب المعلّمين مفتوح؟
Security Guard
الحارس
He isn't answering?!
لا يردّ؟
Did something happen?!
أوقع أمرٌ ما؟
No, he probably just drank himself to sleep again.
كلا، لعلّه ثمل وغطّ في النوم مُجدداً
The guy's still at it, after all these years.
لطالما كان ذلك حال الحارس العجوز منذ الأيام الخوالي
After all these years?
الأيام الخوالي؟
Oh, that's what Ran-neechan said.
ذلك ما قالته ران-نيتشان
I can't really tell them I'm actually a graduate of this grade school...
لا أستطيع إخبارهم أنّي خريّج لهذه الابتدائيّة
But now what? Nothing's happened, so I can't call the police.
،لكن ما العمل الآن؟ لم يقع شيء فلا أستطيع الاتّصال بالشرطة
Which means I'll have to...
...مما يعني أن عليّ
This is the Mori Detective Agency.
أجل، وكالة موري للتحرّي
Oh, Mister?!
عمّ؟
Oh, Conan! Where are you? Ran was worried sick!
!كونان؟ أين أنت؟ ران قلقة جدّاً
Teitan Elementary School! Could you come here?
في ابتدائيّة تيتان! أيمكنك القدوم الآن؟
Come to your school?!
آتي لمدرستك؟
Don't be stupid! I already graduated from elementary school!
!يا أحمق! أنا تخرّجتُ من الابتدائيّة بالفعل
No, I want you and Ran-neechan to come right away!
ليس ذلك، أنا أحتاجك لأن تأتي هنا !فوراً مع ران-نيتشان
Okay! Roger that!
!حسناً، عُلِم
Why does everyone have to be drunk?!
لمَ الجميع ثملون؟
Oh, well. I guess I'll look around the school more until they come.
حسناً، لا يهمّ، سأبحث في أرجاء المدرسة أكثر حتّى يأتون
Wait, Conan!
!انتظر يا كونان
Hey, who was on the phone?
ممن كان ذاك الاتّصال؟
Hey! Dad!
!اسمع، أبي
This is kind of fun!
هذا بهيجٌ نوعاً ما
It is?
بهيج؟
See? It's like we're in a dream!
انظر، يبدو كأنّنا في حُلم
Wh-What is this smoke?!
ما-ما هذا الدخان؟
B-Blood!
!د-دم
It's not blood. It's just red paint.
ليس دماً
Paint?
طلاء؟
Someone's dripping paint onto the handrail!
يسكب أحدهم طلاءً من الأعلى عبر فجوة سور السلّم
It follows the taped-up paper and flows down the handrail!
يتقطّر الطلاء على هذه الورقة الملصقة وينسكب على السور
Then what's this smoke?
ما هذا الدخان إذاً؟
Dry ice for science experiments, with water added.
ثلج جاف للتجارب العلميّة أُضيف له ماء
I found it at the top of the stairs.
وجدتُه أعلى السلّم
Meaning the intruder is trying to scare us away?
مما يعني أنّ الفاعل يحاول إخافتنا وجعلنا نرجع؟
Alright! Let's go up and catch 'em!
!حسناً، لنصعد ونمسك به
There's no point. They'll just get away.
لا جدوى، سيهرب غالباً
But if that's what they want, then...
...لكن إذا كان ذلك ما يريده، فعندها
C'mon, you guys do it, too!
!هيّا، افعلوها أنتم أيضاً
I get it! We're pretending to run away!
!فهمت، نتظاهر بالهرب
Alright!
!حسناً
Hey. Can we go out now?
ألا يمكننا الخروج الآن؟
Yeah.
بلى
What's taking the old guy so long? What's he doing?
لكن تأخّر العمّ كثيراً، ما الذي يفعله؟
What is it?
ما الخطب؟
T-There are people...
!يـ-يوجد أشخاص
...in our classroom!
!في فصلنا
And it's not just one or two people!
!وليسوا واحداً أو اثنين
What?!
!ماذا؟
There are ten! What are they doing in that pitch-dark room?!
يوجد عشرة أشخاص! ما الذي يفعلونه في هذه الغرفة المظلمة؟
So that's the person Ayumi-chan saw!
ذلك الشخص الذي رأته أيومي-تشان إذاً؟
Huh? They're holding something!
ما ذلك؟ يحمل شيئاً
Ah! So that's what this is!
فهمت، هكذا الأمر إذاً
Hey, where are you going, Conan?
أين تذهب يا كونان؟
Isn't it obvious? To catch the intruder!
أليس واضحاً؟ سأمسك بالفاعل
Is this safe?!
أسيمضي هذا على ما يرام؟
Can we really catch them?
أيمكننا الإمساك به حقّاً؟
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
Okay! This is it!
!حسناً، ها هي
Let's get some light...
الأنوار، الأنوار
Yoshida
يوشيدا
What's this? That doll from earlier?
!ما هذا؟ الدمية من قبل
Lots of others are set out!
!الكثير منها موضوع على الطاولات أيضاً
There are plaster figures against the wall...
توجد تماثيل جصّية بجوار النوافذ
There's even an anatomy model...
يوجد نموذج تشريح أيضاً
Parents
آباء
What's that paper?
ما تلك الورقة؟
"Parents"?
آباء"؟"
This reminds me of an Open House...
كأنّه فصل مفتوح
Yes.
صحيح
The intruder used the dolls as students
استعمل الفاعل الدمى كتلامذة
and the figures and anatomy model as parents to practice every night
والتماثيل ونموذج التشريح كآباء للتمرّن كلّ ليلة
for next week's Open House,
لأجل الفصل المفتوح الأسبوع القادم
while wearing a mask to keep from being heard outside.
بينما يرتدي قناعاً كيلا يُسمع صوته خارجاً
Isn't that right, Class 1-B homeroom teacher hiding under the desk...
ألستُ محقّاً؟ يا معلّمة الفصل 1-ب ...المختبئة تحت المكتب
...Kobayashi-sensei?!
!كوباياشي سينسي
He's right! Kobayashi-sensei!
!بالفعل! إنّها كوباياشي سينسي
Then the stories about the moving figures and anatomy model...
القصص عن التماثيل المنتقلة ...ونموذج التشريح الراكض إذاً
Were because she carried them here every night!
لأنّ المعلّمة كانت تحملها إلى هنا كلّ ليلة
The running anatomy model was actually her carrying it hurriedly.
ما التبس عليهم بأنّه نموذج تشريح راكض كانت هي وهي تنقله في عجلة
But you should really focus on being nicer to us instead of this.
لكن عليك التركيز أكثر على معاملتنا بلطف بدل هذا التمرين
Yes! You should fix your child-hating attitude first!
!صحيح! عليكِ إصلاح سلوكك المعادي للأطفال أوّلاً
No, it's just the opposite.
كلا، الواقع عكس ذلك
I actually like you students all so much.
أنا أحبّ تلامذتي لحدٍّ شديد في الحقيقة
I adore my students so much that I couldn't get mad at my last school.
كان تلامذتي أعزّاء جدّاً عليّ، فلم أستطع الغضب منهم في مدرستي السابقة حتّى
But at my first Open House, I got so nervous that it failed horribly.
لكن في فصلي الأوّل المفتوح، توتّرت وفشلت فشلاً ذريعاً
When one boy made fun of me, the one next to him started a fight
سخر منّي أحد الصبية آنذاك، وتشاجر معه الصبيّ بجواره
and they were both seriously hurt.
فتأذّيا بشدّة
I didn't want the same thing to happen at this school,
لم أرد أن يتكرّر ذلك الأمر في هذه المدرسة
so I made myself mean and treated my students strictly.
لذا حجّرتُ قلبي، والتزمتُ الصرامة مع نفسي وتلامذتي
But each time an Open House nears, those memories come back
لكن مع اقتراب الفصل المفتوح، ترجع لي تلك الذكريات
and make it hard for me to handle.
فلا أستطيع الاحتمال
So I would secretly practice like this every night.
أتمرّن كلّ ليلةٍ سرّاً هكذا
You seemed a lot like the boy who started the fight, Kojima-kun,
أنت تشبه الصبيّ الذي افتعل الشجار آنذاك يا كوجيما-كن
so I was especially worried...
لذا كنتُ قلقةً بالتحديد
Kojima
كوجيما
So that's why only Genta's doll was beat up.
لذا كانت دمية غينتا وحدها مهترئة
But as a result, the students fear me and call me a hag...
نتيجةً لذلك يخافني التلامذة، وينادونني بالعجوز الشيطانة
Maybe I'm not cut out to be a teacher...
ربما لا أصلح لأكون معلّمة
That's not true! I know you're nice!
!ليس صحيحاً! أعرف أنّك لطيفة
You're the only one who waters the flowers
أنتِ الوحيدة التي تروي الأزهار
and changes the fish's water after everyone leaves!
وتغيّر ماء السمك بعدما يغادر الجميع
Right?
أليس كذلك؟
Yes. None of the other teachers do that.
بلى، لم يقم أيّ من معلّمي بقيّة الفصول بذلك
We were all saying how rare it is for a hag to do that...
كنّا نقول جميعاً أنّ هذا غريب على العجوز الشيطانة
Basically, no matter how much you falsify yourself,
أي ببساطة، مهما زيّفتِ نفسك
there's no fooling children's eyes!
فلن تخدعي أعين الأطفال
Since the truth's out, maybe you should go back to your real self?
بما أنّ الحقيقة كُشفت، لمَ لا ترجعين لذاتك الحقيقيّة؟
Though in your case, you might have to fix your nervousness first.
رغم أنّ عليك حلّ مشكلة توتّرك أوّلاً في حالتك
I know.
أعرف
But that was mean of you to use smoke and paint to scare us!
لكن كان من القاسي استعمالك !للدخان والطلاء لإخافتنا يا معلّمة
You were the one watching us through the window, right?
كنتِ من تراقبنا عبر النافذة، صحيح؟
No. This is the first time I saw you kids tonight.
كلا، هذه أوّل مرّةٍ رأيتكم فيها الليلة
After I heard your scream, I put the anatomy model back
فاجأني صراخ تسوبورايا-كن، فأعدت نموذج التشريح لمكانه
and stayed hidden in the nurse's office for awhile.
وبقيت مختبئةً في مكتب الممرضة لفترة
Then who unlocked the faculty office door?!
من فتح قفل باب مكتب المعلّمين إذاً؟
The faculty office? What are you talking about?
مكتب المعلّمين؟ ما الذي تتكلّم عنه؟
I knew it!
!كما ظننت
There really was someone!
!كان هناك أحدهم بالفعل
Wait! Edogawa-kun!
!انتظر! إيدوغاوا-كن
There's someone else, inside the faculty office!
!يوجد شخص آخر غير كوباياشي سينسي
There you are!
!ها أنت
A-Assistant Principal?!
نائب المدير؟
Wh-What happened to your head?!
!ما-ما الذي حلّ برأسك؟
K-Kobayashi-sensei!
!كـ-كوباياشي سينسي
The person who tried to scare us away was the assistant principal.
من حاول إخافتنا لنرجع كان نائب المدير
He came here to find the hairpiece that he lost two days ago
سبب قدومه هنا هو لإيجاد شعره المستعار الذي قذفته الريح
when the wind blew it off in the faculty office.
في مكتب المعلّمين قبل يومين
Ohata-sensei created this shocking scene after opening the window.
من صنع ذاك المشهد الصادم كان أوهاتا سينسي بعد فتحه للنافذة
And so the late-night wig-hunt began, but...
وبدأت رحلة البحث عن الشعر المستعار ...الليلية المتأخّرة، لكن
I can't find it anywhere.
لا أجده بأيّ مكان
Let's just forget about it.
لنتوقّف وحسب
No, no! I can't come to school without it!
!كلا، كلا! لا يمكنني القدوم للمدرسة دونه
...In actuality, the principal might've secretly taken it.
وفي الواقع، كان المدير من يحتفظ به سرّاً
It's a perfect alibi...
!إنّها حجّة غياب مُطبقة
But you gave the estimated time of death!
!لكنّك من أعطى وقت الوفاة المقدّر
I will destroy his alibi!
!لا بدّ أن أطيح بحجّة غيابه
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
Next Conan's hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Life preserver.
طوف عوم
Next episode takes place at the beach.
!نذهب للبحر الحلقة القادمة
On behalf of the staff,
...نيابةً عن الطاقم
enjoy your summer!
!نتمنّى لكم صيفاً طيّباً